<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<book>
    <title>Too Tangled to Move</title>
    <author>Marie Malo</author>
    <blurb></blurb>
    <chapter>
        <h1>Chapter 1</h1>
        <p>James’ bicep twitched as the makeup artist rubbed another layer of concealer over the letter’s FTW scrolled across his left forearm. She worked downward, toward his wrist where his favorite tat, a depiction of Van Gogh’s skull smoking a joint, camouflaged a fair amount of scar tissue.</p>            
        <p>He would never have taken this modeling gig had he known they would censor his ink, and his wrist was the last place he wanted to be groped.</p>
        <p>With a slow inhale he planted his feet flat on the floor and focused on the hum of the industrial fan. After seven years of therapy, he ought to be able to calm himself down—without dissociating. But he couldn’t. </p>
        <p>His heart thudded and despite the circulating air, the room grew warmer by the minute. He needed help. </p>
        <p>Luckily, it was close by. </p>
        <p>With a slight twist, he attempted to make urgent eye contact with his friend Caleb who sat one chair over, dressed, ready for the photo shoot. </p>
        <p>But Caleb, who always had James’ back, missed the SOS. </p>
        <p>Instead, he stared down at the open pages of a discarded Cosmopolitan magazine. Weird reading material, even for Caleb, but something had been off with him since school let out for summer. He was too quiet, even distant, and no matter how much James tried, two weeks of prying hadn’t loosened Cal’s tongue. </p>
        <p>James cleared his throat—but got nothing. His stomach tightened.</p>
        <p>“Stay still, [i]por favor.[/i]” The woman frowned as her fingers skimmed Van Gogh. “Almost done.” </p>
        <p>A familiar shiver trickled down James’ spine. One he’d been taught to notice. A warning. He needed out of the chair. Now. Before she asked what happened to his wrist—or didn’t ask—and assumed the worst. </p>
        <p>Slouching forward, hand on his groin, he flashed his most persuasive smile. “Skip that one…Cierra. I’ve got to piss.” </p>
        <p>She glanced at his pants but shook her head. “You’re not moving ‘til I finish your arm.” </p>
        <p>[i]Trapped.[/i]</p>
        <p>The air around him tightened. His body teetered weightless as his mind fought for distance. </p>
        <p>In a last-ditch attempt at staying corporeal, he doodled large circles on the smooth surface of the pop-up table. Another grounding technique, straight from his shrink. </p>
        <p>The exercise helped until Cierra thumbed the patch of skin still sensitive from nerve damage. Nausea rolled over him and a tiny whimper squeezed through his clamped jaw. </p>
        <p>Screw grounding himself. Dr. Madison didn’t know shit. If he didn’t disconnect, he’d knock Cierra on her ass. Once he spaced out, she could do what she wanted with his body. </p>
        <p>He dropped his hand into his lap as a familiar haze slowly blanketed him. </p>
        <p>“James. Stay with us.” With a loud sigh, Caleb let the magazine slide from his knees. He thumped over it as he rolled closer. “Stop messing with him. I heard your instructions. Cover everything R rated, leave the rest.”  </p>
        <p>The tightness in James’ chest receded. Help at last. </p>
        <p>“What does [i]Nár laga Dia do lámh[/i], mean?” Cierra’s Spanish tongue slaughtered the Irish verse wound around a Celtic cross. </p>
        <p>“Leave it.” Caleb’s voice was flat. </p>
        <p>“May God not weaken your hand,” James answered, the conversation a means to keep him in his body, on planet earth. </p>
        <p>Where—according to everyone—he needed to be. </p>
        <p>Cierra selected a foundation brush from a clear plastic bag. “All these tattoos must limit your work opportunities.” </p>
        <p>“Bloody hell, Cal.” James closed his eyes as the brush assaulted his skin but was no longer on high alert. He’d passed that torch to Cal. “I’ll never be gainfully employed. Whatever will I do?” </p>
        <p>Caleb chuckled. </p>
        <p>Cierra didn’t. She tapped the serpent on the inside of his right forearm. “I do like the snake, though.” </p>
        <p>Twisted into a knot and dangling a clover from its mouth, the serpent was James’ biggest tattoo. It hid a long, straight scar—newer than the rest—but like most of his others he was clueless how he got it. </p>
        <p>Not that he cared. </p>
        <p>He turned toward Cierra’s voice. “All the girls like my snake, CiCi.” He waited for Cal’s rebuke, reining him in, telling him he’d gone too far, but got nothing. </p>
        <p>“Keep your eyes and mouth closed, [i]chaval[/i].” Cierra shielded his nose and blasted his arm with setting spray. </p>
        <p>He knocked her hand away. “I’m eighteen. Legal. In case you were… curious.” He wasn’t eighteen yet, but she didn't know that. </p>
        <p>“All done.” Her voice came from his right. “They are still setting up in the next room. Put a shirt on and wait until they send for you.” </p>
        <p>James kept his eyes closed but smiled. He’d managed his stress without dissociating. Sure, he had some help, but only a wee bit. Now that it was over, he felt certain he could have handled it on his own. </p>
        <p>He sucked in a breath and exhaled, rolling the remaining tension from his shoulders. “What do you think, Callie? You’re staring holes through me. Do I look as preppy as you?” </p>
        <p>Caleb’s seat squeaked. “How would you know what I’m looking at? Your eyes are shut.” </p>
        <p>James opened his eyes. Sure enough, Cierra cleaned supplies at the adjacent table, and as he guessed, Caleb stared at him from his chair, his happy pink shirt and white cummerbund at odds with the tightness in his jaw. </p>
        <p>“How would you know my eyes were shut if you weren’t looking?” It was unarguable logic and he waited for a smart-ass reply, but Caleb only scratched the back of his neck and turned toward the long wall of windows. They were high enough up to see Lake Michigan, sandwiched between Chicago’s metal skyline. Scenic, sure, but it didn’t warrant more than a two-second glance. </p>
        <p>James unstuck himself from the sweaty confines of the chair’s black vinyl and scooped up the Cosmo magazine. Are you an enabler? the cover enquired. He dropped it on Cierra’s table then strolled across the wood floor, toward a metal rack containing the required outfits. The first shirt tagged for him, Fitzpatrick, was black with silver pinstripes. He slipped it on, leaving it unbuttoned. </p>
        <p>“Keep the sleeves loose for now.” Cierra’s gaze lingered on his Irish Republican Army tattoo, half-visible above the low waistband of his trousers. Her complexion darkened. “So, how long have you two been a couple?” </p>
        <p>“I like women.” James sat down. “Older ones.” He pushed his hips forward, letting the flat front pants illustrate his package. </p>
        <p>“We’re brothers,” Caleb offered, still facing the windows. </p>
        <p>They weren’t brothers and looked nothing alike. But James smiled at the term of endearment Cal picked up from the years they lived together, courtesy of the Department of Children and Family Services. </p>
        <p>“Twins,” James added, “identical.” He searched Cierra’s face for a reaction. </p>
        <p>She dropped the bag of brushes into her tote. “I know all about you, James. Including how old you are.” </p>
        <p>“Great. She’s been warned about you.” Caleb faced him. “I’m surprised you haven’t gotten fired yet.” </p>
        <p>James dug his smokes out of his backpack. Cierra didn’t know shit about him, and Cal, who knew [i]everything[/i] about him, needed to chill. Cigarette between his lips, he spun the chair on its axis. After a couple lazy rotations, he stopped and leveled his gaze at Cierra. </p>
        <p>“So what do you think? Me and you…” </p>
        <p>Cierra lowered her bright pink tote to the floor and extended the handle. “Aren’t you dating Alexa Petrov?” </p>
        <p>[i]“Dún do bheal.”[/i] Caleb pointed at James; his brows pulled into a stern blond line. “He’s kidding. Tell her you’re not serious—and not breaking the agency no dating rules.” </p>
        <p>James chuckled. Cal telling him to shut his mouth in Irish sounded as funny as Cierra’s use of the word dating, but he said what Caleb wanted. He always did. </p>
        <p>[i]“Si. Mamar gallo.[/i] Of course, I’m not.” </p>
        <p>“Is there anyone at the agency you haven’t slept with?” Caleb asked as soon as Cierra shut the door, “or in the city limits?” </p>
        <p>James shrugged. “I haven’t poked the blonde ride that moved next door.” He meant it as a joke. He caught Caleb spying on her as she unloaded boxes and hadn’t let him forget it. </p>
        <p>“She’s not a ride,” Caleb said with more conviction than a girl they hardly knew deserved. “She’s from Kansas, and I’ve been meaning to tell you, I want to get to know her; do the girlfriend thing this summer, with a regular girl. One not in the scene. Also… I prefer she didn’t know about this.” He motioned to the lighted vanity and rack of clothes in the otherwise barren loft. His gaze rested on James. “Any of this. When girls find out about modeling, they treat you different. You’re in the same boat. Think about it.” </p>
        <p>The sporadic jobs they went on hardly made them models, but James shook his head. Thinking was pointless and introspection was something he got plenty of during therapy.</p>
        <p>He picked his cigarettes off the table and exchanged the smoke for a blunt. One quick hit was all he wanted. “You don’t think this girl will check you out? I guarantee she’s already scoped out your Instagram.” </p>
        <p>Caleb eyed the blunt but let it slide. “I edited my bio and removed any incriminating pictures. Besides, she lived in the country. How much can she know about fashion?” </p>
        <p>“You just called her [i]daft[/i] cause she’s not from the city. Fine way to start a relationship.” Not that he cared how Cal maintained his girls, as long as they stayed out of the way. </p>
        <p>He licked the length of the blunt, the weight in his stomach lighter. If Cal’s issue was getting to know some random girl before screwing her, he’d wasted two weeks of vacation worrying for nothing. Caleb would never put a girl over him. Besides, from the glimpse he got of her, half-hidden behind boxes, she wasn’t even hot. As fair as Caleb, she resembled one of his many cousins, not a dating prospect. </p>
        <p>He shifted the blunt to the corner of his mouth. “When do I get to meet the girl that has you wanting to hide who you are—before you learn who she is?” </p>
        <p>“You’re on a need-to-know basis,” Caleb said, “you have a big mouth. You’d spoil it for me.” </p>
        <p>“I might.” James lit the blunt and inhaled deep. Smoke filled his lungs and would work its magic on his head. He offered up a hit. </p>
        <p>Caleb waved him off. “I’ll introduce you when she wants me so bad, she won’t know who she is.” </p>
        <p>“You mean when she wants you so bad, there’s no way she’d want me.” </p>
        <p>“Whatever.” Caleb frowned. “So, we’re good? You understand, right? I want some alone time with this girl. At the very least, a few solid weeks to focus on her. Besides, Dr. Madison said you need practice dealing with stuff, solo. Think you can survive summer without me keeping you alive?” </p>
        <p>James took another hit then licked his finger and extinguished the heater. In a couple days the girl would be forgotten, and he would have his friend back. When it came to Caleb, solo was not a word their shared vocabulary.  </p>
        <p>He smiled wide, all teeth. “Not a problem. I don’t need you.</p>
    </chapter>
    
</book>
